All rights.
Keep on coming in.
Thanks-a-lotwelcome the san francisco in our build conference my name's ed
...I'm a product manager at microsoft for visual studio online
a lm in our dev ops family...
in here I'm really glad you could join us I'm actually really excited so this is
the first alam and dev obsession for the conference so we're going to go through a
...set of what we're doing and I have a lot of great announcements to let-you know
about...I'm really actually excited more about showing you all the
great work that the team is put together to show you today so to get...started and,
just want to set a little bit of a context as we've gone through the first decade of
agile what we've really noticed is that we've gotten development teams to get really,
really efficient at creating software.
The other thing we saw in the first decade of agile is
...to distinct life cycles we've got the application development lifecycle and
the operations lifecycle and they were they
were very different and now as we move into the second decade of agile
were noticing is that there's a convergence of those
two like a life cycles in the one lifecycle which is dev...
So, today we're going to talk about how do we use dev ops practices
...as a strategic driver toward business agility.
Now there's no question doing business is really tough today and we've talked to lots
of customers across lots of different industries and...three main things that keep coming up.
Basis is getting faster every day and markets can turn on
...on a dime and competition is getting stronger as well
so today's edge that you build becomes tomorrow's mainstream.
Now the need to go from idea to reality
erratically shorten timeframe is really putting huge pressure on development teams to deliver more
quickly.
And, since every company is a software company those that can deliver software
more quickly and better high-quality are going to be the ones that end up surviving.
how is it the some companies like netflix...and...
And, facebook regularly deliver new features
...new value their customers well there's other organizations that wait
weeks and months to deploy those new features so what we end up seeing
is frustration and all sides so if you think about business and are consumers
in titty they're really frustrated because they see a lack of collaboration between the development team
...the operations team?
Now that just increases time...delay and labor involved
in actually delivering and maintaining software which isn't a good thing in a world where we actually have to be quicker.
Now once you add to that
the problem that much of what we build is based on assumptions instead of our data.
And, you can see how this easily lead
...team to end up building the wrong thing.
As...now the inability of delivering software
efficiently and react quickly to changes in the market lead to much more than
just frustration and the long-run this can end up threatening your business now.
In the real-world they're and they're real consequences if
you're enable deliver software quickly and efficiently so,
for example, forty percent of implementations that we
end of seeing end up failing and have to be reworked because they don't end up meeting users
original requirements now when you add to that go there we
go it's really expensive whenever there's downtime are latest estimates about
one hundred thousand dollars for customer-facing apps for every hour that it's down
in production and then if you also peer that with how long it
takes actually fix those problems about two hundred minutes are over two hours?
Becomes really expensive.
Now one good thing that we've been seeing is that we've seen
three-quarters of development teams actually adopting agile methodology
is that's a great thing especially in twenty fifteen but.
It doesn't help of a development team is agile.
But, deployment still takes weeks and months because the...ops team is perceived
as not being agile now these are just three very-high-level examples of many.
...of the many data points that all point towards
the same conclusion and this is more than just about frustration or minor delays
when you have a lack of collaboration between your development team and operation seem
...of having a substantial impact on your business let me tell you a little bit
about our journey in developer divisions so I'm sure,
you know, the developers in the audience of have seen the visual studio releases
for many years they used to be every about three years and we had to switch to
become a lot more quick so we used to have these milestone base releases so, you know,
beta are crt m and they're just really,
really long now before I joined microsoft I was a microsoft and vp
...for many years and I got really good at figuring out windy give feedback to the
pm so, they can take advantage of the feedback and pivot but,
when I joined microsoft in engineering?
As a pm
remember very well wind up having conversations and depending where those conversations we're having,
for example, I had one that was at the end of our release cycle towards our
...is really good feedback from the customer but I couldn't take it I
had to basically tell them well that's really good feedback but I might be able to get to in
about three years and that's just absurd so what we've
Is our organization is actually move to a three-week
release cadence not only for visual studio online which is our cloud-based service but
also you get ctp builds of a visual studio every three weeks now...potentially
separable increments now all of them go out but most of them do and we were able to get feedback a
lot more quickly and for us the key to success was
that close collaboration between development and operations we have to be one team?
So, if you're interested in more about our particular
...you can go to stories that visual studio dot com to get more details.
But, based on what we've learned what we've seen in teams in the industry that
converge step...lifecycle gives you the ability to execute on ideas
quickly iterate on feedback rapidly so you're building the right products now develops
practices emphasize three main things you may have heard of this systems thinking
breaking down of silos and collaboration inflow value note
develops is not so much about tools it's really round people first.
And, then process second and the tools are just there to help you facilitate the
cultural and process changes that you need to make...microsoft the develops investments were making
...of visual studio visual studio online team foundation server
and as a reflect on our focus on
enabling and empowering teams everywhere to get great software and the hands
of your customers now let's take a look at some of the work that we're doing today so I'm going to
go to very-high-level we get a lot of great break out sessions coming in so,
you can get into it deeper but I'm going to give you a whole bunch of stuff right now so
we'll start with the left side of the cycle which is around plan.
really plan is all about how to turn your idea into reality in a
...world is all about hypothesis driven
in creating experiments so we're building tools to help you
out with that so let me show you a few things that we've been working on so let me switch over here.
Okay, the first thing I want to show you is our number-one requested feature
for many years I remember as an dpi I needed this one as well.
So, what you can do now some ago the admin portal many
go to the collection admin view and I can take any one of our team projects and guess what you
can do today rename?
It took us a little while they do that but it's there now
and we've got a much better architecture now after this so this is really
been great so just a little while ago I don't know-how many how many of you voted
on in the room but we had over six thousand votes we just flipped it over from plan
say completed so we shipped out the team foundation server twenty fifteen rc
...available in visual
...online as well so I just I bring this up because.
User voice is actually a really good way to get feedback from your customers we use it
as well but as we've as we use it I'm going to go into
our admin experience here user voice happens to have been one of our partners
...been taken advantage of our extensibility platforms so we've had an open
alam extensibility platform for visual see online for a while that revolves around
three main web standard kind of extensibility points which are rest api
service...and...user voice happens to be one of those so you can see right in here this is the admin
experiences are visual studio user voice account that's connected to
our visual see online account you can just link-up user voices
build some really nice stuff but one thing that they haven't been able to do is something I'm
...today.
So, if I hop over here.
I now have the ability.
To install visual...online extensions now what is that
that's what we're announcing today it's basically a way for partners and
customers to be able to create their own extensions and install them
into their account and then now start to have ui extensibility so you can
...yourself right into our ui our partners...and other services are able to
...they're, they're abilities into our ui now and they show you one of them
we were able to give our in vp early access you see right here I've got a
new team calendars based on some collaboration we did with one of those
...vp so, it's that pull this up really quickly every
go so what's the nice thing about extensions is that you can load your own extensions
are get them from partners but this particular one is a ui that's just being drawn and,
then is pulling data from via so you'll see we've got
our sprint data here I've got you know,
personal days off those are coming from our capacity management system as well as
team days off but I can also add custom data so in this particular one
...build twenty fifteen we'll make this an events?
...go so this is custom data from the extension as well
as our data from via so-and-so now in addition the rest api is in-service folks and o
off...able now to extend in build your own ui inside of our
ui and make it really part of the experience so really glad to announce ...visual
...online extensions today we're going to see a whole lot of great stuff we lots of great
examples hopefully you'll go out and build your own as well but some of the other...presented
...creating things like branch visualizations they were able to customize the cards on the
task boards and...really cool and around...ability of work items and start
to diagram those even our partner each dev has a baseline a solution so we're
going to see a whole bunch of these extensions come out now that they're available and we're all going to be
better for it...one other thing I wanted to show you is a lot of the work that are
teams have been doing around helping you with implementing agile and can
...practices so what...
Me hop back over there.
So, you're not familiar with got a task
board and also can been board we've done a lot of really good work here so the first thing you'll
notice is we've really ramped up the look and feel we made
it a lot lighter it's a lot more usable in their we've done things like being able
...inline add new items right from the can
been board I can edit certain field so I can edit the
assigned to or the efforts right from there I can also start to
show additional field so this is something that's brand-new for example,
bugs I might want to know what their severity and priorities are so we can add any fields that you want on
there you can customize those.
Also we've started the pop the avatars for the different team members on your
team...putting those of their and then also I don't know
...notices you see how we have several different columns here get new approved
spec in progress.
In done well...
in progress we've actually put split columns so if you're familiar with can band there's
this notion that teams pool from the stage before
it can process so we wanted to be able to help you easily distinguish
this so if you think about devon qa...to know what from dev is ready to
pool and then when they're ready to pull the pull it over so you can go and you'll notice that the
done column is what the next team needs to poole from so you can implement can
...practices that way and also we've got some little things so, for example,
like definition of done all of these are customizable
by each teams so each team can define their own sets of definition of
done for each of the columns in there and you notice we got mark down support so you can get pretty rich
Now one thing we've been doing a lot of the customization that has been done
has been done at the process temple level so that means your organization your division
defines most of the customization that happens in here we've changed our
mind set on this and that we want to empower individual teams to work
with the way that they want to instill have guard rails in place for divisional level sets
a processes so what you're seeing now is we're putting a lot of configuration down at the
team level so in this particular one you'll notice we can customize the columns so
every teams allowed to make their own columns move them around define, you know,
definitions of done whether that's a split column if you're
using work-in-progress limits you can also do that from can
...the other part is we can also customize each of the cards so you
by work item you'll notice I can go in for the bug actually put
severity and activity on there and show tags you can customize
...the arts content and you won't be messing up some other team as they go and track their works
...giving a lot of these kinds of settings another one of those
sets of team settings that a lot of people like to do differently I
...when I was process consultant is everyone likes to handle
their bugs a little bit differently so we're allowing every
team to define the way that they actually manage bugs whether...treated as pbr's or
...treated as tasks on the task
...so we give you a lot of flexibility we're going to just keep continuing in doing that
for you so, they every team is empowered to do what they need to do?
Let's switch back over here.
Ok, so, once we have
been planning we move into our next phase which is really around letting developers
and testers do what they do best which is creating software so once
...iterations of started you want you developers to be able to take those great ideas internal
...features so there's lots of different activities here around writing code unit testing
relates around developing quickly and then being really
keeping that quality level really high so let me show you some of the things that we've been doing in this particular space.
First thing I'm going to show you is I've got this my...
applications just a typical enterprise application with...back-end and there's several...so, for example,
reasons ameri and we've got an ios in android project in windows
...windows phone app here ...universal...now.
let me show you a little bit about what we're doing here so one thing that we want to do is we want
to make sure the developers are able to collaborate a lot better so especially
as the code base starts to get a lot larger so one of the very common things they end up happening
is that you as a developer you get something assigned to you have to starts belonging to the code
...figure out what's going on now how many folks are familiar with our code
...feature that's available visual seo great
...so we've got...today we've added of a few new changes in their,
for example, you know, as I pull up the changes view I start to see
who's been contributing to this method or this class at whatever level you want
to go across the many days I can see how many merges of
commonplace but what this is really nice to do is be able to say hey
who's that subject matter expert who understands this particular classroom method
...so you can start to go bother them and their problems and their code so but we've got lots of other
indicators search start to come in we give you this heads up display so one of the things I wanted
to mention was that for the longest time-code lens in visual
...online was one of the very top request that we've gotten so today we're marking
our general availability of code lens inside...visual...online so one more thing I
want to make sure they...now is that we...make sure that all of your
developers have access to it so we've also...lens in visual
...online are sorry envisaged two-twenty fifteen to be available now
in visual studio professional...above so...
As...really hard to do.
But, I'm glad you like that so,
now colons is available is really going to help you start to collaborate better across
or team so it's a big reason why should upgrade visual...fifteen now.
Not only is collaboration important but also keeping quality
up so...really, really key thing so automated units has are actually
your first-line of defense to be able to keep quality especially as you start to
ship software more quickly with the last thing you really want to do is actually
shipped bugs more quickly to production so we don't want to do that so, one thing we're
...visual...twenty fifteen is our new and telecast feature and,...
click run...here and what it's doing is starting to discover
all the different ways that a particular method is being called
now we can talk about code coverage encode coverage just goes in says hr
my set of tests actually covering the lines of code that are in my application but actually
getting high code coverage is not going to be sufficient enough because how many times you have
an if statement and if statement might go and different methods or, you know, every line actually
could start to go lots of different pass especially as you start to look at the methods that are underneath it
...is all sorts of things that happen there so really what you...to do is you want to have the minimal amount of unit
tests that actually cover all the bounds and all the what we call arcs in
the logic of your application so within tele...we will discover the minimal set of
test so, for example,...pass in null for the employee
...the employee class or I might go in and say three sixty and then...
a complex types...actually start to figure out what are all the combinations that we need to do their
and now instead of just having height code coverage you're now going to start to have
...are coverage because at any point in time?
Save that set of unit test...it's going to create a whole unit test project
for you and that set of tests ...have a great
our coverage from that so this is really going to help developers
starts to get a great sweetie of automated
tests just to get started with anyone like that...error rate.
Yeah, it's a great set of stuff and telecast intel tests
is now available in visual see twenty fifteen...to kick the tires in the release candidate
so give that attract now let me pop this open here.
Now the other thing you need to do in order to keep quality up is not only have
a set of automation but a lot of times you just need to get another set of humanized
...additional set of humanized on the code that
...introducing a production so we do that through
...reviews whether that's through code reviews are...requests so we have a very rich
pull request system inside...visual...online when you're
using get or code reviews if you're using team foundation version control but,
you'll notice interpol request system you're able to see all the poor
...are coming in I have one assigned here for me and pull it up from sachin?
All right cool okay so let's take a look at is progress.
I looks like he has
...topic branch here and, he's merging a master so actually probably should make sure that
his code is pretty good you'll notice we've got several different files that are part of this
poor request there's a discussion going on here that will come back to if I
go over the code you'll see there's a couple of commits happening here all right that's cool
...a new line
their new file is a bunch of changes in here so...to take a look at that
...also can keep track of what work items so what bugs are tasks are being implemented in this
pull requests if we want to go take a look at the requirements or details about those we can go do that
as well better come back to the discussion you'll notice
a couple different things are checking to make sure there's no merge conflicts if...end up being any
will keep track of multiple commits but you'll notice we have a discussion going on here
...odb ranking take a look at the fair calculation logic michael said it looked
okay photo michael said in do that too okay I think this looks okay so?
Looks like...
rate logic okay I'll add that in there.
And, these are just inline discussions that are happening into the line of code and then we can
mark each of these threads is being done or not so over time we can actually keep
track of all the information that were gathering for this but you imagine if you're
...regulated industry all this great information that you can set your auditors in front of
...a lot of really good stuff but we can also
track responses for teams with the reviewer so I can assign a
...request to the whole team and anyone can pick up and start to review from it or
consented to specific people so I'm actually
okay with this change semitic go in I could I could set rejected or waiting for
...those are always fun when we do that internally but,
I'm going to say it's approved approved with suggestions and you'll notice I
...it's now saying that it's ready to go let me the target
branches updated so let's track...conflicts...not going to be
able to push that one so that's okay I could just as soon as someone approves it
is long as there's no like denys we can go in and complete that poor question it will go
...behind-the-scenes for us so it's a really awesome...system and,
we're really happy about doing that so that's
one another way of wvu being able to increase the quality of the code that you're pushing
through to production now another thing that we have.
Is how many folks are familiar with sonar cube, yeah,
right so sonar...is actually really popular solution
in the dropper world and really it's all around have managing your
technical debt now technical that all is a set of problems...end up impeding
forward progress in your ability just to continually put new value to customers
so that's everything from like code issues in bugs and all sorts of stuff ...
really you want to be paying that debt off over time you don't want to let it start to snowball because eventually
you'll end up spending fifty percent of your time on just managing the technical
...you have so what we've done is we partnered with sonar
source who's the creator center
...to actually integrate this is part of the build process for both
team foundation server visual stew online and the other thing that's really nice is java developers of
love sonar sort or sonar q for a while?
Now dot net developers have access to sonar...soon...
cubes so we're going to now I'm going to show you have got I've got a csharp project in
here we're starting to get things like lines of code files functions if I
sort of pop in here I am also
noticing that I have lots of different issues and if I open up one of these issues
are actually tell me where in the code that is finding those issues and we can keep track of these
...the really important things that you want to do is keep track from build...build
whether creating you debt are paying that debt off so you can do that with sonar
...today now if you're not familiar with kind of where this...within the overall
lifecycle you actually do this type of analysis after
the compiles stage so you turbine areas it goes through and
...to do this analysis so that's part of the build process forty
so I'm really happy to have sonar center cube integration now with visual
...online and team foundation server...is alleviate...here I think you might be up
at the booth but olivier is the ceo of sonar source and he's here at the
bil conferences so-if you have any questions you-can come see...up at the visual...online
booth so all right now the other thing I wanted to talk about is
our new next generation build system.
we got into build if you're familiar with our...system...always had a really great
...system but one thing that we couldn't do was very
easily was actually compile other types of applications so what I wanted to start
out with is that we've built a brand new build system and we've
open-source the agent and the tasks.
And, I'll show you with us tasks look like in a second but these are all node js space these are
open-source we wanted to facilitateecosystem and
have everyone contribute the best build tasks out there in build on top of
ours in contribute more so the everyone takes advantage of that so those are right up there
on get have right now and then if I show you are new system?
All right let's pool this one up now edits.
The one big thing is now instead of editing your build definitions
and customizing them in a windows workload
file we now have that experience up in the web and it's a whole lot easier now to do so,
for example, is just task base so you say hey this particular
...is going to go in and build visual studio it'll build my android
out my ios app zooming components etc and all it is a set
of build steps so these are those node dspace tasks that run on our
...js based build agent that can
then run on windows on linux on...else no
...will or runs so it's a great new addition to our new generate
our new build system we've got lots of great stuff to get started great all
you've got ants you can run x code...all of these and we've got lots of
different other activities that you can do and I'll talk a little bit about those in a second?
But, if I go in and I show you a couple of things you'll notice we can
also decide where our repository is
so if you're hosting your visual...your...get repo inside
...visual seo online we can take advantage of that obviously but
if you're hosting your get repo in another provider like get hub or
...some other provider you can actually use are build system
with those providers as well so we're able to do that today too couple of other things,
things like...can...variables throughout the build tasks that you have going on inside of
your build process triggers things like continuous...integration if you want to build every
...we can schedule those so hey I might want to do a nightly build.
The other thing is if you're if you've been with the
...build system for a while I know that I used to be a bil guy myself
and my team we also get used to get really frustrated about this but now we have the ability of
actually tracking configuration changes to the to your builds so
we'll keep track of every single one of those and we can also
...those so we used to like to play who messed up the build process and,
that was that was awful but, now we're able to do that today so,
the new...simulate you keep track of all those.
Okay,
now last thing I want to do and...kill that one.
I'm actually going to q a build in this is going to be my ios
...from that my subtle application and...I think we're good here.
Let's see so what I'm doing here is I'm actually yet there
...eight so I'm actually compiling running tests on
my ios application and this is are no js agent happens to be running on a
mac and you can bring your own build server or you can whether that's
...premises or in the cloud or you can use our build
servers in this particular case I brought my own mac
...a cloud dot com is a service that you can run max and I
...agent on there and I just ran and ran have my build
for my ios application and then at the end of that all those binary skit
ship back to visual...online and we can we hold your
...folders you can get to at any time so
...really nice thing is we won't hide your logs everyone...don't hide my
logs so we're now giving you live logs that are coming from those build agents and then
we'll capture those for you to investigate a little bit
later so it's great stuff we even parallelize things if you want to debugging
...build will actually do those in parallel a lot of really good stuff in our new build system
so feel free to take advantage of that will be shipping that very soon for everyone and,
then now also be and team foundation server twenty...really good...there?
All right let me switch back over here.
Right.
Now that we've gotten our...process done we now have a set of a binary
...so what we need to do is we actually need to get to production at
this point but there's usually a few steps to get their...they have to go to devin
qa pre production and you at and all sorts of other
environment's and if we're going to speedup...
that feedback cycle we need to be able to ship a lot more quickly so with this phase
what we're really trying to do is take all the manual steps out of out of what your...
release processes and automate those and model those in a way that makes sense
to your organization so let me show you a little bit of what we're doing here to be able to do that.
Yes,...that page.
All right.
Now first thing we want to do is there's
...set of tests that they end up running so it's not just automated test but you may end up having
other build verification tests functional test those kinds of things so, one
...that we wanted to be able to do is make sure that your developers and testers are able
to get access to what's happening in the system so if I come over here.
And, open up one of our builds here it looks like it's failing and,
we've always been able to capture the actual
...results of those automated tests so you can hear you splint you can start to look at,
you know, there's lots of errors in of different tests that are going on but we
needed to give you a better experience here so if I come up top here we have a
new test results analyzer that we brought from microsoft
...manager moved into the web in given you a new web experience
and now we're able to start to give you a good view of what's happening in
those test runs now this just
happens to be a set of automated test but if you are also using exploratory tester
manual tests any of any the tests that we allow including you can turn your
j unit test results into test results...get...we're going to aggregate all those
for you...give you some really good information so you notice I have thirty automated
test in this particular test run in ten of them look like they're failing and, I can see
will...by priorities so how many are passing failing by the priority so your ptwo
...usually has more in
...kelso track to see and let your tester start to identify the
failures so in this case we don't need to know...failure take for all of them
except for these failed ones so we can start to do.
So, I can come over to the individual test results themselves and let's see if I
can find on-the-field...do this one.
All right so we start to get information here this one just happens to
be really simple test but if you are doing a manual test in the
test-market failed you can get the recordings of the video logs screen
shards tele trace browsers all sorts of stuff that will show here and,
then you can go in and create a bug in it...create a really nice
...bug with all that data and it ties back to the test results
are itself here so you get a lot of really good trace ability but I can also after
...your tester can go in and say hey, yeah, this is regression or to new
issue we can keep marking those so that when we go back to.
...see here we go back to here will update that
...for view so that you can start to see for that particular test
...what were all the different failure types so we'll whole
lot better test result experience here so...stuff there.
Now the other thing that we're doing is based on our based
on our acquisition of any release which is release management technology we
spend some time actually moving that experience up into the web and actually making...lot better
so I'm happy to show you for the first-time our new release management experience.
So, this is built on top of the build system
it uses the same exact agents so those are all...dsp base
...dspace agents they also use the same task infrastructure
so now we're able to start to model what are released pipeline
looks like so you can start to create stages that the end up matching your environment's
we're going to give you a really good view about where releases...different points in time so,
for example, in this particular one you
...crm release I can see like what build is actually in the
dev environment right now and I can see that's been passing for some time so that's a really good thing so
the two-point-zero builds in dev I've got the one-point-seven building qa and
...one-point-five...serum but we're going to give you a whole lot better information
...here now the one thing that we should go and take a look at is I'm going
to go and take a look at some of the releases that is that...happens.
Yeah, I haven't done any today so let's bring that up there we go let's go back
to the one-point-five release we can start to actually get really good data about what
happen with this release so you say hey when did
...go out it went to mon actually we were pretty good about sipping that very quickly.
You see some activity the artifacts this happens to use a very
specific build or builds from your system we also get the logs so
for every single one of the activities that we end up defining which I'll show you in a second we can start to check
...happened there we can get to the raw logs that are from there so we're getting a
...a lot of great information for you to be able to look back on and especially for
those of you that are and regulated industries you're going to want to show your auditors these kinds
of things so now let's take a look at actually editing what
...release pipeline looks like so if you'll
many pool this right here?
See that were getting cut off a little bit there you go so now I can start to define
the different stages and then what happens inside those stages so, for example,
in the dev environment I can start to run our shell
and different machines I can just do a whole lot of different things inside of here including,
you know, running a set of selenium testify one-two
...cloud-based
...tests in that environment to make sure it's okay
I can do a lot of different things and I can define what we do in each of those
environment's is really easy to add additional tasks just like our build system we can
pull from that same task library in these are going to be deployment specific tasks that you do in
there so imagine I can...as your I can
deploy to darker containers I can run a chef deployment I
can do all sorts of different things that happen a maps each of those environments that you have?
Now it's really easy each of those has their own configuration options I can also go
in add new environment so if I want to add...
And, then move that environment up
...is many stages...as I want into this process and we
should know also in that world we may not have builds going all the
way through so we want to catch failures before they move on to the next phase so we'll be able to
track that there now another thing that you might want to do especially for those of you who
are in regulated industries is you don't you don't want everything moving
from stages stage all the way through sometimes what we need is the ability to
...human approval so we're able to actually track those as
...come here, you know, our.
Of vp brain...if I can spill is name...bra in there we go
will have brian...clemency?
Be the approvals before it gets deployed out into production so once
I do that anything that makes...the next point will actually ask each of them
to prove this before it goes on so typically
...apps person we'll end up being the person that does those but
we'll track those approvals as well that gets checked into our database and
...of having trace ability for all those as well so
...are new experience for release management really,
really easy-to-use and, we hope that that's going to be really helpful
...start...track all of your releases.
All rights.
Now may move back over here.
And, finally we move into the last face so now that we have moved
our builds into production one of the big challenges that we have in
dev ops implementing devils practices and making sure that we
dot only release quickly but we end up learning
quickly and we need to be able to learn quickly so that we can build the right product
for our customers so really that's where we are here and we want
...take advantage of what we can learn from production so we do
that using a service where providing is application insights as part of visual
...online and what we're denouncing today is that we're
moving application insights into being a public preview service so the other thing
we're announcing is that in december we made...acquisition of hockey app if you're familiar
with them we're taking the capabilities around ios
...crash analytics and we've now incorporate that into application
insights as well so we got pricing details including a free
...available but let me actually show you what application insights looks like?
Now there's three main things that you're going to want to think about as we want to learn from
production so that is my application available is it performing
And, then ultimately how're my users using my application so first I just
wanted-to give you a sense of what this is application insights is what is
are service and you just start to...data of from both your...
servers and, the server-side as well as your client devices so you think about
mobile devices in tablets in all of those other devices that could...putting
up data so I just pulled up our get have repo here that shows you all the different st
...that we do have available so,
you can contribute your own as well and we'll just keep adding to this
list as we have as we keep going on but you can literally send data from
any part of your application and what we'll do is we'll take all that data and give you a three hundred sixty
degree view of what this of what your application is doing so if I look at for some
...look at our back-end set of services so we're getting all sorts of
really great information so let me...getting cut off again here so I'm in?
Every...all right cool so if you'll notice I'm
giving a good overview of what's happening here.
You'll see hey, you know, that we're getting a really good
...response time the page loads are pretty good get lots of server
...that's great
lots a users only bad thing is we have some failed requests here so we're
...want divx ended deeper here but how many developers typically have
access to production to be able to figure this out, yeah, not...
So, what we're doing is we're trying to give this data into developers hands so the
first thing that we usually want to know about...is...application available so if I look
into availability what you'll notice is that we can now start to have
both simple ping tests as well as complex tests and we'll run those test
for-you from data centers around the world to let, you know, before your customers
...when your app is down so I think we're doing pretty good here we can start
...get some more details about what's going on there we've got a few failures and we can go in
and dive into the details but pretty much were looking pretty good and whenever there is a problem we'll go ahead and
email you whenever we notice something so you can get your development team on it as quickly as
possible now the other thing?
The other thing that we want to do is we actually want to understand what's happening
with these failed these failures so if I come over here.
And, a click on failures we can start
to understand what's happened so you notice I've got some failed requests here.
I've got on different, different pages so, for example,
this is...app so we've got search
controllers about controllers looks like the search pages getting a lot of hits there I
can also see the types of exceptions that are happening so if I click on this top one here.
Let's see let's pull this up array we get an exception here.
And, now I'm certainly give really rich information about what's happening including
lines of code the types of applications I can dive in deeper
...wanted to figure out the call stacks, for example, like
in filter out just my code or see the whole thing and I can start to understand where
...exceptions are happening so I can get back to code very quickly so if I want to I can also look at
the telemetry for that particular user session where happen and I can start to see what they were doing so they
hit the home page and then they started to get a bunch of exceptions
...capturing all this great data that's happening on the server-side
and shipping that back-up so the developers can start to get in
resolved there problems a lot quicker and get to
...cause analysis all right so that's one part of it as well?
The other part about application
...sizes learning what your customers are doing and how they're using the
application so we've really...usage analysis you notice...can I
can take a look at different things like you know, number of users
the types of events there the types of features that they're using so we can start to see what are
...most popular features so that we can
make investment decisions and decide whether to pivot
or persevere based on the usage so we're getting lots of really great data here but,
what's really nice is the ability to define your own metrics so these are what we
call custom events someone open up the coast custom events view?
And, this is where your developers can start to define different metric
point so, for example, we've got symmetric points for how features are being used so,
every time a feature hits a certain point we can ...data...and will aggregate those
for-you that's a really good thing is we can start to collect all sorts of other information behind-the-scene so,
for example, in our my shuttle app what ends up happening it's a very much like
...huber...so that people are searching for cabs and those kinds of things but,
one thing we might want to know is average trip cost
so this is a custom event that we've gone in aggregated
we're going to start to bring that data into the view here?
There we go so now you're certain a-c overtime the different average trip cost
per day so these are these custom events for you to be able to set your own hypothesis and,
understand where
your customers are using your particulars part of the application so this is a great part
of application insights and finally the last thing I want to show you is really
around our new device capabilities so this is understanding
how your customers are using all the different devices that you have across all the different platforms so you think
about android ios in as well as windows-based platforms.
So, what you can...we're starting to get even information from their
use a got lots of users lots of sessions page views I can search the
...in deeper you're also getting feature analysis you can understand the
top features from your customers on your device apps where they are
around the world so this is really important information the device types
there's a really great but the other thing...notice is we're actually getting a fair
number of crashes that are happening so I know that we've released a new
the new app versions so let's see what's going on here all right so we've got
a hundred seven users that are impacted so we need
...taking a look at those so if I started grab here this is actually come
in again notice that this is coming from swift in my ios
up and yet sure enough that latest version is causing some
more problems here so we saw a few times before but we're actually seeing a lot more
...dive in deeper here concerted take a look
at the exceptions and we use technology called symbolic education behind-the-scenes to start
to get to information like the call stack and line
members and we can figure out devices and we can also start to take a look
at the customer journey for how they got there so if I look at the telemetry for that
particular user session I can notice what are the actually doing before they got that
crash so if I pool this down here?
Okay, they check the cab status they
...cabin in the exception happens and that's when we got the data back for that
so this is already starting to give you a lot better information about helping you get
to root causes analysis but also we can start to make good decisions and speedup
are process so that were learning the right thing so that we can build the right things for
our customers so this is application insights in a nutshell we've got a lot of great stuff you can
go in and give it a try in the as your portal today so it's rate
there right alongside your infrastructure and you're going to get a lot of really good stuff out of that.
Okay, so, let me move back over here.
Now I really wanted to give you a sense of how microsoft is
been investing in dev ops across the entire life-cycle in really
our solution with team foundation server whether you want to run it on premises or use visual
...online which is our hosted version of...fs and related services we
want-to make sure that every team is empowered to be able to
implement abouts practices and get better building software quickly in building
...right software so we have lots of capabilities here you know,
for java developers for eclipse developers and x code developers
...all able to...jump in now with lots of great capabilities in a
release management service or build service with
get repost work item tracking all of those things are now available for every developer
and every team across your organization and so.
I showed you a lot of what we've already built
and what's available or things that are soon-to-be available let me tell you a little bit about kind
of our road map ahead in how're thing about futures and really that surround for key
themes so the first one being helping...customers
...customers scale agile so...a few things like
reporting support the starting with our by with visual studio online we're going to
lets you customize your work items as well and then if we move forward there's
another theme around collaborating on code a lot better so there's a couple things in
here one I like to point out usually is having a hosted packets management service
we have new get up here but we're also making sure that we cover other very popular
packets management's solutions like m pm and others and, then if we think about continuous delivery
is another theme of investments we're wanting to help you out with as part of the
released pipeline you want to make sure that you can efficiently use
...part of each stage so we're going to make some
...test lab management enhancements so that you can provision new
environment's and d provision them at the end of this at the end of the...
Can help you efficiently use infrastructure for devon test purposes and,
then finally as we think about learning from production we're going
to do things like better dash sporting support and then move application
insights onto the journey towards general availability so lots a
great stuff...the teams already done in lots a great stuff that she will continue to
do we just touched on a several of those but really what I'd like to do is we're going to
dive in deep onto at each piece of what we showed you today
...donovan has a session right after this around new release management system but,
you can go way create your own visual
...online account for free you can tryout application insights for free as well?
And, then also be sure to take advantage of downloading the visual
studio twenty fifteen release candidate as well as...team foundation server twenty fifteen
release candidate and then finally we've got some giveaways going on apologies
...have enough time for questions but I'll stay here afterwards and,
then we are also all going to be working at the...cs at the visual...online in the
...and dev ops booth so will be there I'd be happy
to answer some questions for you there and then finally be sure to help the
...and let us know what you think by evaluating the session and
...me so I'll be here for it but thank you so much for being
here are build and go find the other alam sessions as well and
diving deeper thanks-a-lot moi.